Charles A. and June R. P. Ross Archives
Yale Peabody Museum of Natural History
- Miscellaneous, Series II
  - Publication material., 002482
    - Publication/Research Source Material. Mostly Pre-1973 - Four roadmaps, three of Arizona and one of New Mexico, annotated with "Localities to do [AZ]," "Localities Studied [AZ]," and one unannotated [from AAA; Arizona New Mexico]; the map from New Mexico is labeled "Needham's Localities"; 10 interlibrary loan requests from C.A. Ross for various publications pertaining to Paleozoic marine fauna and stratigraphy; various, handwritten lists of publications pertaining to sections investigated by C.A. Ross for his 1973 publication, paleoceanography, paleogeography and paleotectonics in Arizona and New Mexico; pages from various publications of paleogeographic and paleotectonic illustrations spanning the Paleozoic from Nevada, Utah, Colorado, Arizona and New Mexico; handwritten lists of publications from various countries (e.g., Tunisia, China, USSR (CCCP), France); one index card with a single citation regarding Paleozoic and Cenozoic stratigraphy in Apache County, Arizona; a black and white photocopy of a portion of the Tombstone, 002864
    - Reference Lists. Charles A. Ross - 1980-1983 - Reference lists of published articles, including 1) a reference list of Late Paleozoic formational nomenclature and 2) a reference list of publications released within the "Monographs on Upper Paleozoic Paleontology", 003063
    - Reference Lists. Charles A. Ross - 1958-1959 - Shipping invoice from USNM regarding USNM loan 226646, sent to C.A. Ross 1 Sept, 1959, containing specimens of unidentified goniates from the Permian of the Glass Mountains; several handwritten pages by of notes by C.A. Ross detailing references and data of Penn/Perm ammonoids and brachiopods collected from the midwest and western USA; two handwritten pages detailing recalled discussion between C.A. Ross and G.A. Cooper after his trip to Washington D.C. [dated November 15, 1958]., 003101
    - Reference Lists. Charles A. Ross - 1982-1984 - Typed and handwritten reference lists of published articles, books and other media compiled by C.A. Ross during (and after?) his investigations of the Pennsylvanian-Permian stratigraphy of Nevada; the handwritten component of these reference lists includes four ~3"x5" cuts of paper., 003155
    - Sample Lists. One typewritten report (1972) and one xeroxed copy of a report (1975) by C.A. Ross pertaining to specimen identification via thin sections from rocks sampled by J.G. Monger in 1967; handwritten notes on samples from J.G. Monger analyzed by C.A. Ross which remain unpublished (see Associations Tab; Appendix A)., 003017
    - Sample Lists. Charles A. Ross - Two lists of samples collected by Peter K. Link in NW British Columbia (Atlin area) for his Ph.D. dissertation (one xeroxed, one typed); three small notepages with handwritten notes relating to specimen and age determinations, by C.A. Ross, for some specimens collected by Peter K. Link; one typed list of Link's collections from which Skinner [1965] reported fusulinids., 003006
    - Specimen Identification Report. Charles A. Ross - 1959 - Report on referred fossils (USNM), conducted by I.G. Sohn on behalf of C.A. Ross in the identification of ostracodes present in 13 slides of material, sent to Sohn by Ross in January 1959. Sohn's report, completed in Feb 1959, is typewritten in blue ink and contains his overall thoughts on the final page of the report., 003103
    - Specimen Photography & IDs. Charles A. Ross & Jim Monger - Specimen photography and associated specimen identifications of fusulinid-bearing bulk-rock samples collected by Jim Monger and analyzed by C.A. Ross; two xeroxed lists of specimens analyzed by C.A. Ross (marked 1 of 2 and 2 of 2, respectively)., 1966-1975; 003011
    - Talk Materials. Charles A. Ross and June R.P. Ross - Post-1997, Pre-2012 - One typed transcript and supporting figures (2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7a, 7b, 8 and 9) for a talk presented at an unidentified symposium, sometime during or after 1997, titled "The Tethyan origin of the Far-Travelled Atlin Terrane (Carboniferous-Permian), Northwestern British Columbia"; one typed copy of the abstract associated with the talk., 003012
    - Rejected manuscript, reviewed copies of manuscript, and letters from both GEOLOGY and PALAIOS. Manuscript entitled, "Sea-level fluctuations in the Upper Ordovician Cincinnatian Series", 1996-1997; 002770
- Photographs & Negatives, Series III
  - Information about Photographs & Negatives., 002919
    - Locality information. list of thin sections which have been photographed from the central states cores, 1960-1970; 002917
    - Specimen IDs & ID References. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1963 - Handwritten list of specimen identifications for C.A. Ross' fusulinid photography from sections #19-22; handwritten ID reference list for support of Wolfcampian fusulinid identifications included., 003121
    - Specimen IDs. Specimen identifications for C.A. Ross' specimen photography of fusulinids from Leonard-Word sections 1, 2, 2A, 3, 4, 4A, 5, 5A, 6, 6A, 6B, 6C, 7, 7A, 7B and Jail Canyon and Clay Slide sections (see Associations tab)., 1957-1960; 003074
  - Miscellaneous Photographs & Negatives., 001321
    - Aerial Photography. Charles A. Ross - Aerial photography of the Glass Mountains area, West Texas; includes index map of aerial photographs, along with zoomed-in photographs of exposures from various imaged strips; includes a courtesy copy of an aerial survey (#290 c) performed by Edgar Tobin Aerial Surveys (San Antonio, TX; Scale 1" = 6,000')., 1954; 002904
    - Color Photography. Charles A. Ross - Color photography of the Glass Mountains area, west Texas, including outcrop photography, photography of the town of Marathon, TX and surrounding areas and photos of field trip participants, possibly from the Chevron field trip and/or prep photos for the Permian Basin SEPM field trip; includes two illustrations, one by C.A. Ross (1987) which may have been used as teaching tools during the field trip(s)., 002905
    - Film & Thumbnails. Charles A. Ross - 1957 - Kodak film and thumbnails of photographs of landscapes and outcrops in the Glass Mountains area, West Texas. Some photographs are annotated with a black "X"; these photographs were later enlarged., 002907
    - Miscellaneous Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1965-1968 - 45 unannotated black and white photographs of landscapes and stratigraphy in Arizona, and one annotated page of smaller, black and white photos marked "Arizona March 1968.", 002868
    - Negatives. Charles A. Ross - Negatives of stratigraphic sections from SE Arizona and core descriptions, well logs and well log correlations from Texas., Jan 1989; 002753
    - Negatives. Charles A. Ross - 1960 - Negatives of a table of stage names in the standard geologic column in Russia (then U.S.S.R.) developed by V.V. Drushchits and K.V. Kurdykov (1959) and adopted by the geology faculty at Moscow State University. May have been part of a field guidebook published by C.A. Ross on Spitsbergen, Svalbard, Norway., Oct 1960; 002900
    - Negatives. Charles A. Ross and Willis W. Tyrrell - 1965 - Hand-drawn stratigraphic section of Figure 2, negatives of text figures 4 and 5, and negatives and group traces of foraminifera reported in plates 75-78 of Ross and Tyrrell (1965); A handwritten copy of the abstract for the publication., 002869
    - Negatives. Charles A. Ross - Negatives from C.A. Ross' Spitsbergen field guidebook, including plates of geologic maps (from the Interngational Geological Congress) and comments on stratigraphy of Svalbard, Norway., 002901
    - Outcrop Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1957 - Black and white outcrop photography from the Glass Mountains, West Texas; some photographs are annotated with assigning images to partial stratigraphic sections published by P.B. King and C.A. Ross or of partial sections of formations without assignment to a particular publication (e.g., photo labeled as "most of Gaptank Fm")., 002906
    - Photographs & Negatives. Black and white prints and negatives of foraminifera and bryozoa specimens; as well as negatives from field trips, professional talks, and papers. Three large boxes of black and white prints attached to 5x8" cards contain specimen from the following dates: 1948 (10-21, 10-22); 1958 (5-22, 5-23, 8-14); 1959 (8-19, 8-21, 8-23, 8-24, 8-25, 8-26, 8-27, 8-28, 8-29); 1960 (7-23, 7-24, 7-26, 7-27, 7-28, 7-29); 1961 (11-1, 11-5, 11-20); 1963 (2-6, 5-3, 5-4, 5-5, 6-11, 6-12, 6-13); 1964 (6-5, 6-6, 6-7, 6-8, 7-11, 10-24), 000984
    - Photographs & Negatives. Aerial photomosiacs of the Glass Mountains made by Tobin Aerial Surveys. Used and annotated by C. A. Ross (formation outcrop extents traced onto images), 002935
    - Photographs & Negatives. Color photographs of gardens (Nevada?) and the landscapes of the state of Nevada; some outcrops and features such as folds, faults, and unconformities are photographed; photographs are accompanied by negatives, but neither the negatives nor the photographs themselves provide locality data for the places pictured., 003154
    - Specimen Photography & Negatives. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1983 - Fusulinid photography from bulk samples collected by C.A. Ross; fusulinids are sourced from sections #11 through #20 in the Glass Mountains (West Texas), detailed in Ross's GSA Memoir 88, "Standard Wolfcampian Series"; negatives from C.A. Ross' Chevron field trip to the Glass Mountains, W. Texas (1983)., 003117
    - Specimen Photography & Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1950-1959 - Fusulinid photography from bulk samples collected by C.A. Ross; fusulinids are sourced from miscellaneous Wolfcamp [Neal Ranch and Lenox Hills Fm] localities; photo duplicates of fusulinids collected from various miscellaneous samples collected at the Wolf Camp Hills; large (~6" x 4") photos of outcrops in the Wolf Camp Hills and Glass Mountains area; one cardboard-backed plate of fusulinids of the upper Gaptank Fm collected from the Prouddenites locality, 4.5 mi S, 15 deg. E of Lenox, Texas (P.B. King and C.L. Baker)., 003128
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1967 - Specimen photography of fusulinids collected from the John Day and Merlynd Nestell localities, Oregon., 10 Jan 1967; 003085
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1969 - Specimen photography of fusulinids originally enclosed with correspondence between C.A. Ross and M.D. Dasch; list of specimen photography noting specimens published (with figure directory within the paper)., 18 Sep 1969; 003076
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - Specimen photography of thin sections from PN localities 4151 thru 4156; each PN sample has photographs at different magnifications [1982-1983]; a note written by C.A. Ross (December 1996) indicates specimens and/or specimen photography from PN localities 4158-4164 [Beatty, Nevada area] are missing., 1982-1996; 002997
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1957 - Specimen photography of fusulinids collected in the Eagle Mountains (W. of Van Horn), West Texas., 25 Jul 1957; 003077
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1956-1958 - Specimen photography of fusulinids collected from localities near and within the Glass Mountains, West Texas; includes a sheet of all collection localities and several handwritten lists of specimen IDs and notes from specimen localities derived from C.A. Ross' stratigraphic sections (#1-7 (including 4A, 5A, 6B, 6C) and U.S.N.M. localities (of form '7XX-LOWERCASELETTER'), 002909
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1958 - Fusulinid photography from bulk samples collected by C.A. Ross; fusulinids are sourced from sections #1 through #10 in the Glass Mountains (West Texas), detailed in Ross's GSA Memoir 88, "Standard Wolfcampian Series"; 18 small, 2" x 2" photographs taken at the Lenox Hills, ~2.5 mi NW of Decie Ranch house., 003113
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1958 - Fusulinid photography from bulk samples collected by C.A. Ross; fusulinids are sourced from sections #21 through #30 in the Glass Mountains (West Texas), detailed in Ross's GSA Memoir 88, "Standard Wolfcampian Series"; most specimen photos are from sections 21 and 22, with few from sections 26 and 29., 003120
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1958 - Fusulinid photography from bulk samples collected by C.A. Ross; fusulinids are sourced from sections #33 through #42 in the Glass Mountains (West Texas), detailed in Ross's GSA Memoir 88, "Standard Wolfcampian Series"; specimen photos are from sections 33, 37, 40, 41 and 42., 003123
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1960 - Specimen photography of various fusulinids collected from C.A. Ross sections 23-32, 34-38, 40 and 43 from the Glass Mountains, West Texas; four pages of notes detailing miscellaneous Gaptank Fm collections from the Glass Mountains area, West Texas, 003028
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1960 - Specimen photography of various fusulinids collected from C.A. Ross' Leonard-Word Section 3, Glass Mountains, Brewster/Pecos counties, Texas; 11 pages of notes detailing specimen IDs to accompany specimen photography., 003066
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1960 - Specimen photography of various fusulinids collected from C.A. Ross' Leonard-Word Section 4, Glass Mountains, Brewster/Pecos counties, Texas; 22 pages of notes detailing specimen IDs to accompany specimen photography., 003067
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1960 - Specimen photography of various fusulinids collected from C.A. Ross' Leonard-Word Section 5, Glass Mountains, Brewster/Pecos counties, Texas; 0 pages of notes detailing specimen IDs to accompany specimen photography., 003068
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1960 - Specimen photography of various fusulinids collected from C.A. Ross' Leonard-Word sections 6, 6A, 6B and 6C, Glass Mountains, Brewster/Pecos counties, Texas; 0 pages of notes detailing specimen IDs to accompany specimen photography., 003069
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1960 - Specimen photography of various fusulinids collected from C.A. Ross' Leonard-Word sections 7, 7A, 7B, Glass Mountains, Brewster/Pecos counties, Texas; 0 pages of notes detailing specimen IDs to accompany specimen photography., 003070
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1957-1960 - Fusulinid photography from bulk samples collected by G.A. Cooper at several USNM collection localities in the Glass Mountains, West Texas, and processed by C.A. Ross w/ accompanying identifications [see Associations Tab]; some pages contain handwritten notes by C.A. Ross., 003102
    - Specimen Photography. Charles A. Ross - 1965-1966 - Assorted specimen photography associated with stratigraphic sections from SE Arizona New Mexico and Colorado, some of which are published in Ross (1973), not stored with photographs relating to their parent section(s). Dates and sampling localities with these specimen photographs are crossed out, circled with question marks written next to them, or otherwise contain indeterminate information as to the identity of the original section to which they belong. One exception is 8-24-66A, a page of specimen photography from Ross' Rio Piedra section at Sheep Creek (Needham's Locality)., 002867
    - Black and white photographs of specimens taken from the thin sections of R. Blodgett's Farewell Mtn specimens [bryozoans], 002733